<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on Hacking Management</title>
    <link>https://lacoski.github.io/tags/twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on Hacking Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2018, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lacoski.github.io/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving the most viewed presentation on slideshare ever at OSCON</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/how-i-gave-the-most-viewed-presentation-in-the-history-of-oscon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/how-i-gave-the-most-viewed-presentation-in-the-history-of-oscon/</guid>
      <description>Steve Francia at OSCON   At OSCON 2012 in Portland I gave a presentation on building your first MongoDB application. Over 150 people were in the audience, a pretty significant number of this type of hands on tutorial. Certainly worth the weeks of preparation that went into developing it. While at OSCON I put the slides online at SlideShare where during the four day conference the amassed over 20k views and within a couple weeks over 30k views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch what you say</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/watch-what-you-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/watch-what-you-say/</guid>
      <description>shh.. Gustty    I came across an article today titled “Help! My boss is on twitter“. Allow me to share a secret with you, if you current boss isn’t on twitter yet, I can guarantee that your next one will be. Social media has caught on like wildfire. In all the excitement too often people forget that everything that you say on twitter / facebook and others is being published and recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Better Follow Friday</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/a-better-follow-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/a-better-follow-friday/</guid>
      <description>Follow Friday is a common practice on Twitter where many people spend friday posting things like #FF @aplusk @guykawasaki … This practice is distracting at best and fails to accomplish the single purpose it intends. Follow friday began as way to share lesser known twitter users with your community. A great idea that quickly grew out of control. I propose a better implementation that will not only accomplish the original intent but will do so in a non-distrcting manner by leveraging twitter lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Seth Godin Get It?</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/does-seth-godin-get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/does-seth-godin-get-it/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week Seth Godin announced his first presence on twitter with the post Delivering blogs via Twitter..
 You can receive instant daily updates of this blog by following @thisissethsblog. I create the tweets automatically using a service called twitterfeed. It’s free and it works really well. (PS this is my only presence on Twitter… I’m focused on the blog and my books, and alas can’t tweet and do that at the same time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>54% US Companies Ban Social Media... and That&#39;s Fine</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/54-us-companies-ban-social-media-and-thats-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/54-us-companies-ban-social-media-and-thats-fine/</guid>
      <description>According to a study commissioned by Robert Half Technology, an IT staffing company, 54 percent of U.S. companies say they’ve banned workers from using social networking sites like Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and MySpace while at work. Source: 54% of Companies ban Facebook, Twitter…
We should be shocked that this number isn’t higher. Let’s look at this realistically. For many professions, networking is crucial to success, but in most professions, it is personal networking, not online that is beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Your Social Media Presence</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/managing-your-social-media-presence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/managing-your-social-media-presence/</guid>
      <description>As social media continues to emerge, many professionals are curious on what is the best way to manage these various networks. For posting updates I have found ping.fm an invaluable resource. I use it to manage updates across all my networks including Twitter, Facebook,LinkedIn, Flicker, FriendFeed and more. Here’s the skinny on how I utilize this resource.
If you’re not familar with ping.fm it enables one to post updates to one or many different websites though email, web, IM, SMS and widgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Social Media</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/ranking-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/ranking-social-media/</guid>
      <description>In business it’s common to use sales as a metric to determine success. Songs, albums, books and movies are all ranked on “best seller” charts. While this isn’t a perfect metric, it is largely useful due to the innate control built within. There is friction to a sale in that buying something costs money of which people have a limited supply. This makes it so that someone couldn’t just repeatedly buy their own song, album, book or movie and have a best seller (not to mention they would be losing a ton of money to the distribution and retail channels).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Web Sites (LAMP) : Top Resources</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/scaling-web-sites-lamp-top-resources-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/scaling-web-sites-lamp-top-resources-2/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia   Luckily it’s 2009 and there have been a bunch of successful websites that have had to deal with large scalability challenges. Many have been kind enough to share their knowledge with the world. Here is a list of the best books, articles, presentations and practices from the likes of Twitter, Facebook, Flickr and more.
Books Building Scalable Web Sites Building, scaling, and optimizing the next generation of web applications by Cal Henderson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Twitter from Becoming the next MySpace</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/stop-twitter-from-becoming-the-next-myspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/stop-twitter-from-becoming-the-next-myspace/</guid>
      <description>Image via Crunchbase   6 months ago Twitter was the best place in existence to use and develop great relations with key players in industry, brilliant thinkers and friends. It has since become popular, and like the kids trying to be popular in high school, has become a whore. Not that it was ever exclusive by restrictions, but rather by obscurity. Now twitter is being over run with spammers, marketeers ( is there a difference ), robots, celebrities, fake celebrities, ghost writers and a whole flood of me too people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Meets Twitter &amp; FriendFeed</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/facebook-meets-twitter-friendfeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/facebook-meets-twitter-friendfeed/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase   For the past few months Facebook has been obsessed with Twitter. It’s easy to see why. Twitter is addicitve. Many twitter users are constantly on twitter. Whenever you goto twitter there is always something new happening. Facebook obviously wants this experience on facebook. Why not copy twitter. I think Facebook could do it and do it better. Last week Facebook unveiled their new home page layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Your Next Consultant Using Twitter</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/hire-your-next-consultant-using-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/hire-your-next-consultant-using-twitter/</guid>
      <description>At Portero we had an issue with our network.
I know enough about networking to understand the basics. I actually used to work on the IOS back during the dawn of the internet. Though things have changed since then, the biggest issue is I don’t remember enough to fix network configuration issues on the router level.
Before I took the post at Portero, we had a company we contracted to configure all of our Cisco equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are you not on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/why-are-you-not-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/why-are-you-not-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia   Over the last 2 weeks I have found myself asking that question more times than I can remember. When I first heard about microblogging—or Twitter, the primary service that started the microblogging movement—over a year ago I thought it was a stupid fad and wouldn’t last. I mean what value can possibly be passed along in 140 characters or less. 2 weeks ago I was convinced to try Twitter and I am hooked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>