<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facebook on Hacking Management</title>
    <link>https://lacoski.github.io/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facebook on Hacking Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2018, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lacoski.github.io/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch what you say</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/watch-what-you-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/watch-what-you-say/</guid>
      <description>shh.. Gustty    I came across an article today titled “Help! My boss is on twitter“. Allow me to share a secret with you, if you current boss isn’t on twitter yet, I can guarantee that your next one will be. Social media has caught on like wildfire. In all the excitement too often people forget that everything that you say on twitter / facebook and others is being published and recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>54% US Companies Ban Social Media... and That&#39;s Fine</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/54-us-companies-ban-social-media-and-thats-fine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/54-us-companies-ban-social-media-and-thats-fine/</guid>
      <description>According to a study commissioned by Robert Half Technology, an IT staffing company, 54 percent of U.S. companies say they’ve banned workers from using social networking sites like Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and MySpace while at work. Source: 54% of Companies ban Facebook, Twitter…
We should be shocked that this number isn’t higher. Let’s look at this realistically. For many professions, networking is crucial to success, but in most professions, it is personal networking, not online that is beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Your Social Media Presence</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/managing-your-social-media-presence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/managing-your-social-media-presence/</guid>
      <description>As social media continues to emerge, many professionals are curious on what is the best way to manage these various networks. For posting updates I have found ping.fm an invaluable resource. I use it to manage updates across all my networks including Twitter, Facebook,LinkedIn, Flicker, FriendFeed and more. Here’s the skinny on how I utilize this resource.
If you’re not familar with ping.fm it enables one to post updates to one or many different websites though email, web, IM, SMS and widgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Facebook in Depth Review</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/new-facebook-in-depth-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/new-facebook-in-depth-review/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase   Facebook just unveiled their biggest change yet. The http://www.new.facebook.com website is a preview of the next design of Facebook. The new design places more emphasis on friends and actions and downplays the applications. There is a lot more than just design going on. They also reveal some new functionality. I will present an in-depth review of what to expect from Facebook complete with screenshots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Web Sites (LAMP) : Top Resources</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/scaling-web-sites-lamp-top-resources-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/scaling-web-sites-lamp-top-resources-2/</guid>
      <description>Image via Wikipedia   Luckily it’s 2009 and there have been a bunch of successful websites that have had to deal with large scalability challenges. Many have been kind enough to share their knowledge with the world. Here is a list of the best books, articles, presentations and practices from the likes of Twitter, Facebook, Flickr and more.
Books Building Scalable Web Sites Building, scaling, and optimizing the next generation of web applications by Cal Henderson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Meets Twitter &amp; FriendFeed</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/facebook-meets-twitter-friendfeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/facebook-meets-twitter-friendfeed/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase   For the past few months Facebook has been obsessed with Twitter. It’s easy to see why. Twitter is addicitve. Many twitter users are constantly on twitter. Whenever you goto twitter there is always something new happening. Facebook obviously wants this experience on facebook. Why not copy twitter. I think Facebook could do it and do it better. Last week Facebook unveiled their new home page layout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>