<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Hacking Management</title>
    <link>https://lacoski.github.io/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Hacking Management</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2008 - 2018, Steve Francia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lacoski.github.io/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development&#39;s Magic Triangle</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/software-developments-magic-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/software-developments-magic-triangle/</guid>
      <description>There’s an old adage “Fast, Cheap, Good; Pick Two”. This situation is called a magic triangle. You can have two and only two, if you try for all three you will compromise all three. Fools often try, losing everything.
In the world of software development, another magic triangle exists. You can pick any two of the three, but not all three, so figure out what’s truly important.
Fixed Schedules Fixed Features High Quality Unfortunately business owners rarely have visibility into the last one (Quality).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fascinating interview with Steve Jobs and Bill Gates</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/fascinating-interview-with-steve-jobs-and-bill-gates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/fascinating-interview-with-steve-jobs-and-bill-gates/</guid>
      <description>In 2007, All Things Digital held a fascinating interview with both Bill Gates and Steve Jobs.
The interview runs long and is spread out over multiple clips. I’ve only included the first handful here. Watch the rest on youtube.
It’s clear that they have a reasonably good relationship and clearly know each other well. They have a genuine and sincere respect for each other. It’s amazing how firm a grasp both have on the industry as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s iconic presentations</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/apples-iconic-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/apples-iconic-presentations/</guid>
      <description>Image via CrunchBase   Recently a book came out The Presentation Secrets of Steve Jobs: How to be Insanely Great in Front of Any Audience. Jobs has mastered the art of presenting. I thought it would be interesting to look at his presentations over the years. Here are the three biggest announcements Apple has made.. iMac (Jobs first product after returning),iPod, iPhone.
Look at how his personal style has changed over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How RIM handed the mobile market over to Apple</title>
      <link>https://lacoski.github.io/post/how-rim-handed-the-mobile-market-over-to-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lacoski.github.io/post/how-rim-handed-the-mobile-market-over-to-apple/</guid>
      <description>Image representing iPhone 3G as depicted in Crunchbase   Hint: It has nothing to do with touch screens.
While RIM scrambles to create the next greatest device, or their “iPhone killer” it needs to recognize that it’s no longer about the device. RIM don’t you remember that touchscreens aren’t new.. Palm had them back in the 90′s … before you crushed them.
When RIM ruled the world RIM knows what it takes to dethrone the current market leader.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>